[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
Next, we're going to explore a different approach for
وسنقوم بعد ذلك باستعراض طريقة مختلفة
finding simpler decision trees.
لإيجاد شجرة قرار أسهل.
We're going to grow them all the way and we're going to try pruning.
وسنقوم بزرعها على طوال الطريق، وسنحاول تقليمها.
And the way we going to prune it is kind of like stopping criteria when
وتعد الطريقة التي سنقوم بالتقليم من خلالها، نوعًا يشبه إيقاف المعايير
the prune thing that don't improve our error enough.
عند تقليم الأشياء التي لا تقدم تحسينًا كافيًا للخطأ الخاص بنا.
So, we have two ways to try to find simpler trees.
ولهذا، فإن لدينا طريقتين لمحاولة إيجاد شجر قرار أسهل.
One way was to stop recursing earlier, and
إحداها، تكون من خلال إيقاف التكرار مبكرًا،
the second one was to expand and then prove.
والأخرى، تكون من خلال التمديد ومن ثم التثبيت.
Let's explore the second one, because it's a great complement to the first.
ودعونا نستعرض الطريقة الثانية، حيث إنها تعد تطبيقًا أفضل للطريقة الأولى.
Our goal is going to be to take the complete way that we learned by going
وهدفنا هو أخذ الشجرة المعقدة والتي تعلمناها
too far.
من خلال الابتعاد كثيرًا.
Man, going too far and somehow top of some stuff remove it and
صديقي، قم بالابتعاد كثيرًا وحدد بعض الأشياء وقم بحذفها
then simplify it in order to come up with what
ومن ثم قم بتبسيطها للحصول على
will be a better way in terms of true error.
الطريقة الأفضل فيما يتعلق بالخطأ الحقيقي.
So, here's a kind of motivational picture.
ولهذا، فلدينا صورة من الصور التحفيزية،
You might end up with a complex tree if you don't stop too early and
والتي قد تنتهي أخيرًا إلى شجرة معقدة إذا لم تتوقف مبكرًا جدًا
you can imagine trying to come up with some fancy way to stop earlier.
ويمكنك التصور ومحاولة القيام بذلك بطريقة أخرى تمكنك التوقف مبكرًا.
But instead of doing this,
ولكن بدلاً من القيام بذلك،
you just go a little too far and then we're going to back track.
يمكنك فقط الابتعاد بقدر أقل قليلاً ومن ثم العودة مرة أخرى للمسار.
So we're going to start from this complex tree and
ولهذا، سنقوم بالبدء من خلال الشجرة المعقدة،
we're going to simplify it until we get a reasonable tree that has
وسنقوم بتبسيطها حتى يمكننا الحصول على شجرة معقولة،
maybe higher training error, but has better true error.
والتي ربما يكون بها خطأ تدريب أعلى، ولكن بها خطأ حقيقي أفضل.
The fundamental question though is what makes a tree simpler?
والسؤال الأساسي هو، ما الذي يجعل الشجرة أسهل؟
Clearly, if it have a super
بوضوح، إذا كان لديك شجرة عميقة للغاية
deep tree on the left versus there's a shallow tree on the right.
على اليسار مقابل شجرة سطحية على اليمين.
So in other words, if you're looking at depth,
ولهذا، وبصيغة أخرى، إذا كنت تتناول العمق،
then it is a here's a technical term that I like to use.
فهناك مصطلح فني أفضل أود استخدامه،
No brainier.
وهو البساطة.
It is a no-brainier that the tree on the right is simpler than the tree on
أنه يتميز بالبساطة حيث إن الشجرة على جهة اليمين أبسط
the left.
من تلك التي على جهة اليسار.
So, is depth the measure we want to use to quality what complexity of these trees is?
لذا، هل العمق هو القياس الذي نود استخدامه، لتحسين التعقيد الذي تكون عليه تلك الأشجار؟
It turns out that depth is not a very good metric and the reason is the core
ونستنتج أن العمق ليس مقياسًا جيدًا، والسبب في ذلك
problem is that some features might have more values than others.
المشكلة الأساسية التي تنتج من أن بعض الميزات بها قيم أكثر من الأخرى.
And so, some features might lead to more splits than others.
وبالتالي، قد تؤدي بعض الميزات لتقسيمات أكثر من الأخرى
So here, both trees have the same depth.
ولذا، لدينا هنا شجرتان لهما نفس العمق،
And so the question is which one is simpler?
والسؤال، أيٍ منهما أبسط؟
And we will see this problem all the time.
وسنلاحظ وجود هذه المشكلة في جميع الأوقات.
And intuitively, the more leaves you have, the more complex the tree is.
وبديهيًا، كلما زادت أوراق الشجرة، زاد تعقيدها.
So we're going to introduce this function, L(T),
ولهذا، سنقوم بتقديم هذه الدالة (L(t،
which just measures the number of leaves the tree has.
والتي تقوم فقط بقياس عدد الأوراق للشجرة،
And so the tree on the left here has five leaves,
ولهذا، فإن الشجرة التي على جهة اليمين بها خمس أوراق،
the tree on the right has two leaves.
وتلك التي على جهة اليمين بها ورقتان.
And so we're going to say, the tree on the right is simpler.
ولهذا، يمكننا القول إن تلك الشجرة التي على جهة اليمين أبسط.
And now, we're getting somewhere interesting.
وبذلك تكون الأمور أكثر إثارة،
So now, we can start talking about the complexity of decision trees.
حيث يمكننا البدء بالحديث عن تعقيد شجر القرار.
So for example, this super complex one on the left had the number of leaves here
ولذلك وعلى سبيل المثال، فإن الشجرة المعقدة جدًا والتي على جهة اليسار بها عدد من الأوراق
was one, two, three, four, five, six while the one that's too simple on the right.
والذي يساوي ست أوراق، بينما الشجرة التي على اليمين بسيطة للغاية،
The number of leaves it had was one and
حيث يوجد بها ورقة واحدة.
somehow I want to find a solution in between.
وبشكل ما، أريد العثور على حل بينهما.
A solution in between will allow us to adopt the logical deeper some branches
سيسمح لنا الحل بتبني أعمق الفروع،
shallower in others, but try to keep the number of leaves as good as possible.
وتلك الفروع الأخرى السطحية، والمحاولة بقدر الإمكان الحفاظ على عدد جيد من الأوراق.
And so just like other areas in machine learning,
وكذلك، وكما في المناطق الأخرى في التعلم الآلي،
we're going to introduce some kind of trade off between these two concepts.
سنقوم بتقديم نوع ما من المفاضلات بين هذين المفهومين.
The two concepts we want to trade off to the two quantities are how
والمفهومان اللذان نود المفاضلة بينهما،
well my tree fits the data and what the complexity of the tree is.
هما ما مقدار تناسب الشجرة مع البيانات وما مدى تعقيد الشجرة.
So the total cost is going to be a measure of fit and a measure of complexity.
ولهذا سيكون إجمالي التكلفة عبارة عن قياس لمدى التناسب والتعقيد.
We saw this in regression.
ولقد شاهدنا ذلك في الانحدار،
We saw this in logistic regression.
شاهدنا ذلك في الانحدار اللوجستي.
We're seeing this again in decision tree.
وشاهدنا ذلك من جديد في شجرة القرار.
Here, the measure of fit is just classification error in the training data.
ويعد قياس التناسب هنا، عبارة فقط عن تصنيف الخطأ في بيانات التدريب.
So training error and the measure of complexity is going to be number of
ولهذا، يكون خطأ التدريب وقياس التعقيد هما عدد الأوراق،
leaves, and we're going to balance the two.
وسنقوم بالموازنة بينهما.
So more specifically, we're going to use Error(T) to node the error,
ولهذا وبشكل أكثر تحديدًا، سنقوم باستخدام خطأ (T) لعقد الخطأ،
classification error training data and L(T) to note the number of leaves.
وتصنيف خطأ بيانات التدريب ونستخدم (L (T، لمعرفة عدد الأوراق.
And as we will see,
وكما سنرى،
we'll have a magic parameter to trade off between those two quantities.
سيكون لدينا معلم سحري للمفاضلة بين هاتين الكميتين.
In particular, we're going to use lambda to denote that magic parameter that
وعلى وجه الخصوص، سنقوم باستخدام λ للاستدلال على المعلم السحري
we can fit then for validation set where we have cross validation.
والذي يمكننا ملاءمته لمجموعة التحقق حيث يكون لدينا تحقق متبادل.
When lambda equals 0, we're back to the standard decision tree learning process.
عندما تساوي λ صفرًا، فإننا نعود إلى عملية التعلم لشجرة القرار القياسية.
When lambda is infinite, we have infinite penalty.
وعندما تكون λ لا نهائية، فإن مجموع القيم المطلقة للمعاملات سيكون لا نهائيًا.
So we're going to have infinite penalty,
ولهذا سيكون لدينا مجموع لا نهائي للقيم المطلقة للمعاملات
which means we're going to just learn a tree that
والذي يعني أننا سنتعلم فقط شجرة
has no decisions in it, so just the root.
ليس بها قرارات، ولهذا فهي فقط عبارة عن جذر.
So, we're going to learn something like this.
ولهذا، سنقوم بتعلم شيء من هذا القبيل،
Root and then a class.
الجذر ومن ثم الفئة.
And in this case, we're just going to say that y hat for
وفي هذه الحالة، سنقول أن ŷ
all data points is the majority class.
لجميع البيانات هي الفئة ذات الأغلبية العظمى.
In other words, lambda is equal to infinity.
وبصيغة أخرى، فإن λ تساوي مقدارًا لا نهائيًا.
We're just going to output the majority class, when lambda is equal to 0,
وسنحصل على الفئة ذات الأغلبية العظمى، عندما تساوي λ صفرًا.
it's crazy deep decision tree.
ولذا، فهي شجرة قرار عميقة مضطربة.
When lambda is in between, that's where we came here.
وكما حدث هنا، عندما تكون λ في المنتصف بينهما،
So, this is going to balance the fit and the complexity of the tree.
فسينتج عن ذلك توازن بين التناسب والتعقيد للشجرة.
More specifically, we're going to go from that complex tree to a simple
وبشكل أكثر تحديدًا، سوف ننتقل من تلك الشجرة المعقدة إلى شجرة بسيطة
tree by using a pruning approach where the pruning is based on this function,
باستخدام نهج التقليم حيث إن التقليم يعتمد على هذه الدالة،
which balances the Error(T) plus lambda times the number of leaves in T.
والذي يوازن الخطأ (T) بالإضافة إلى مضاعفات λ، لعدد الأوراق في T.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]